# **Felipe Reis**

<u>falreis.eng.br</u> github.com/falreis linkedin.com/in/falreis

A full-stack software developer for web and desktop environments since 2006. Extensive experience working on large-scale projects in accounting, education, and finance industries. Highly proficient in ASP.NET C#, PHP, and relational databases. Master in Computer Vision (Region Segmentation and Edge Detection), using Deep Learning..

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: Python, ASP.NET C#, C++, PHP, JavaScript, HTML

Databases: Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MSSQL

Frameworks/Libraries: Tensorflow, Keras, Angular, jQuery

Other: Scrum, Git/GitHub, SVN, Google Cloud Platform, Amazon AWS, Anaconda, Jupyter

## **Work Experience**

## IFMG - Campus Formiga - Temporary Professor

Formiga, Brazil | July 2020 - February 2022

- Professor in Computer Science (Graduate) and Informatics (Technical Level) programs.
- Classes: Artificial Intelligence, Operational Research, Numerical Analysis, Discrete Mathematics, Machine Learning, Metaheuristics (in Computer Science program) and Operating Systems (in Informatics program).

#### Reis Eng. e Software Ltda. - Freelancer Developer

Belo Horizonte, Brazil | January 2018 - current\*

- Development of web, desktop and computer vision applications.
- Technologies used: ASP.NET C# 4.7, Angular, Python, Tensorflow, PHP (Wordpress).

### **Prodabel** - Information Technology Analyst

Belo Horizonte, Brazil | May 2014 - July 2017

- Gathered and analyzed requirements to define solutions, developed and supported new accounting software, CASP a Brazilian standard for public accounting;
- Migrated an old accounting software to the new version (including data), developed procedures for accounting processing/closure, developed reports, allowing publish the balance sheet based on the system's data.
- Technologies used: PowerBuilder 12.5 (Desktop), PHP Zend 1.1 (Web), Oracle (Database)

# **<u>Ci&T Software S.A.</u>** - Full Software Engineer

Belo Horizonte, Brazil | July 2013 - March 2014

- Developed and supported an educational software (academic and financial areas);
- Technologies used: Classic ASP (Web), Oracle (Database)

## **CSI Services Ltda.** - System Information Developer

Belo Horizonte, Brazil | September 2012 - June 2013

- Gathered and analyzed requirements, created Scrum Backlog, defined system architecture and developed new software to manage company's printers and hardware resources (outsourced company);
- Technologies used: ASP.NET C# 4.0 + NHibernate (Web), MSSQL (Database), C++ (CUPS)

#### **Education**

PUC Minas, Brazil - Masters in InformaticsDecember 2020Udacity - Self Driving Car Engineer Nanodegree ProgramMay 2018PUC Minas, Brazil - Industrial Engineering, Lato sensu post graduationOctober 2017CEFET-MG, Brazil - Computer Engineering, B.S.December 2012CEFET-MG, Brazil - Industrial Computer, Technical LevelDecember 2005

#### Other Information

Language Skills - Portuguese (native), English (proficient), French (intermediary proficiency)

Scientific Research - 5 papers, published in conferences and magazines

Detailed information and work experiences before 2012 - please visit my LinkedIn profile.